TEKANO MBONANI

St. David Str, 6 Ankehof, Willows, Bloemfontein | 068 152-4516

| mbonanits@ufs.ac.za | www.linkedin.com/in/tekano-mbonani | https://github.com/T3kan0 |

Data Analyst | Quantitative Analyst | Web App Developer

Providing data-driven, action-oriented solutions to challenging problems

An experienced Data Analyst inspired by bringing about action-oriented solutions to data-driven complex problems. With a set of interdisciplinary expertise, I can extract knowledge and insights from noisy, structured and unstructured data/databases. Additionally, I can apply the extracted information to support decisions across a broad range of domains through reports, forecasts and research papers.

EXPERTISE

- Data and Quantitative Analysis
- Decision Analytics
- Predictive Modeling
- Data-Driven Personalization
- Dashboards

- Big Data Queries and Interpretation
- Data Mining and Visualization Tools
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Research, Reports and Forecasts
- Web Application Development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF FREE STATE. (Centre for Teaching & Learning and the Department of Physics)
Data Analyst (2022 - Present) | Teaching Assistant (2021 - 2022) | Research Assistant (2018 – 2021) | Laboratory Assistant (2017 – 2018) |

Conducted administrative duties on various databases and contributed to the development of automated pipelines built to handle large volumes of data for research purposes.

- ❖ Developed an automated, user interactive A-STEP tutorial attendance impact report pipeline for all faculties on the UFS Bloemfontein and Qwa-Qwa campuses.
- * Responsible for tracking, reporting and visualization of the weekly A-STEP attendance data.
- ❖ Uploaded, downloaded, analyzed, and processed complex data sets from/on to the UFS data management systems, i.e., QuestBack Essentials, PeopleSoft and Blackboard, making use of advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Developed several data-driven Web Applications for the preparation, analysis, and reporting of the attendance data.
- * Contributed to the research and presented at various conferences, leading to proceedings of science.

Teaching Appointments: Taught undergraduate courses in Physics, Astrophysics and UFS Skills module (UFSS1504/1522) as a Laboratory Assistant at the Physics Department and Teaching Assistant at the Center for Teaching and Learning, University of Free State.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF FREE STATE | M.Sc. Astrophysics | B.Sc. Hons Physics & Astrophysics | B.Sc. Physics & Astrophysics |

OF NOTE